charityjob.co.uk 2019-04-04

# Privacy and Cookie Policy | CharityJob

**Last updated: May 2018**

CharityJob is a trading name of JobLadder Limited and is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. 

This policy (together with our Terms and Conditions) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. "Personal Data" is information that might help identify you as an individual, such as your name, contact details, IP address or CV. 

We are focused on the protection of your personal data and privacy, so please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. **By visiting using our website[www.charityjob.co.uk](https://www.charityjob.co.uk/) you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.**

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 and the GDPR, **the data controller is JobLadder Limited** of Milton House, 33A Milton Road, Hampton, Middlesex, TW12 2LL. 

We collect and process personal data according to this Privacy Policy. CharityJob collects your personal data from the following sources: (1) data you give us and (2) data we collect about you. 

  1. **Data you give us**

Most of the personal data we collect is provided freely by you when filling any forms* on the CharityJob website or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. 

*An example of a form is at registration: when you create an account with us, you submit your name, your email address and your CV. These are all pieces of personal data we collect and process. **If you do not wish us to collect and process this type of data, then do not submit it when using our services.**

Other pieces of data you give us includes information you provide when you enter a competition, promotion or survey, and when you report a problem with the CharityJob website. 

  2. **Data we collect about you**

For each of your visits to the CharityJob website, we will automatically collect the following pieces of data: 

    * **Technical information** , including the Internet Protocol ( **IP** ) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, and operating system and platform; and 
    * **Information about your visit** , including the full Uniform Resource Locators ( **URL** ), download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from the page, and any phone number used to call our customer service number. 
    * **Cookies** (see the section about cookies further down) 

The personal data you give us or we collect may include the following. 

**From your CharityJob account, it may include:**

  * Your name 
  * Your contact details: address, e-mail address, phone number 
  * Educational background and employment history 
  * Skills and professional qualifications 

**From a job application, it may include:**

  * Your CV 
  * Your job application details 

**From when you respond to a marketing email, it may include:**

  * Answers and preferences submitted to a survey 
  * Answers submitted when entering a competition or prize draw 

  1. **What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that are stored on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. 

The CharityJob website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of CharityJob. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse CharityJob and also allows us to improve the CharityJob website. Depending on the purpose, we may use session cookies (which remain on your browser until you leave the site) and/ or persistent cookies (which remain on your browser or hard drive for a longer period of time). 

You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of the CharityJob website. 

  2. **What type cookies do we use?**

We use the following categories of cookies: 

    * **Strictly necessary cookies.** These cookies are required for the operation of the CharityJob website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into any secure areas of the CharityJob website. 
    * **Analytical/performance cookies.** These allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around the CharityJob website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way the CharityJob website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily. 
    * **Functionality cookies.** These are used to recognise you when you return to the CharityJob website. This enables us to personalise our content for you. 
    * **Targeting cookies.** These cookies record your visit to the CharityJob website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make the CharityJob website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose. 
  3. **Cookies and third parties**

**Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control.** These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies. 

We use third party tracker and data analytics service providers including Google Analytics and [Hotjar](https://hotjar.com/) to help us to understand how people use the CharityJob Website and our services. You can find more information on Google Analytics and opting out [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en). You can opt out of Hotjar [here](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out). 

We do not share the information we gather using cookies with anyone else. We assume that you have no objections to our use of cookies in this way. 

The data we collect and process serves the following functions: web development, marketing customer service, finance and business intelligence. Each one of these functions entices several purposes of processing data, detailed below. 

  1. **Web development.** This includes: 
    1. Using CharityJob (allowing you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so); 
    2. UX customisation (personalising and customizing your user experience of the website, like your personal dashboard, or our personalising the emails you receive); 
    3. Online applications (filling out the application received by a recruiter when you submit an online application); 
    4. Product management (improving existing or developing products and services, which includes research, troubleshooting and testing). 
  2. **Marketing.** This includes: 
    1. Email targeting (sending you targeted emails about jobs or news that might interested you). These emails are sent based on your email subscription preferences, if you have unsubscribed from these then you will not receive them. 
    2. Advertising (measuring or understanding the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you) 
  3. **Customer service.** This includes: 
    1. Account management (managing your account details, including login credentials, registered preferences or history of purchase if you are a recruiter); 
    2. Contact and queries (processing any contact or query received by email or phone, or notifying you about a change in our services). 
  4. **Finance.** This includes processing payments and credits, as well as prevent fraud. It is only applicable to recruiters. 
  5. **Business intelligence.** This includes data analysis and website analytics, statistical and surveys purposes, as well as research. 

Other uses of the data include: 
  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information and products that you request from us; 
  * as part of our efforts to keep the CharityJob website safe and secure; 

We rely on the following clauses as a legal basis for the collection and processing of your data: 

  1. **Consent**

Some of the personal data we collect and process is done with your consent. For example, we rely on consent when we send you a marketing email if your email subscription preferences indicate you are willing to receive such emails. You have the right to withdraw consent at any time. See more information about your rights to withdraw consent further down. 

  2. **Legitimate interest**

We also process data when it is in our legitimate interest to do so and when this interest is not overridden by your data protection rights (see further down for more information about your rights). 

Our legitimate interests ensuring that the CharityJob website is operating effectivity and that you (as a user) can make use and benefit of all of its services (e.g. browsing or applying to a job, posting a job, getting notifications and recommendations about jobs you may like, etc.). It also includes ensuring the security and integrity of the CharityJob website. 

Full details of all our legitimate interests are laid out in our data audit which can be viewed on request. 

Finally, CharityJob may process your data to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations e.g. preventing, investigating crime or working with law enforcement agencies. 

CharityJob may share your data with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006. Access to personal data within CharityJob and JobLadder is strictly restricted to those individuals who have a need to access the information for our business purposes. 

CharityJob may also share your data with the following selected third parties: 
  * Business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we may enter into with them or you; and 
  * Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of the CharityJob website. 

We will also disclose your personal information to third parties if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply the CharityJob Website's terms of use, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers, or others. 

Your data is securely stored and kept inside the European Economic Area (EEA) using access controls and encrypted passwords. 

We will regularly review our retention of your personal data and delete any personal data which is not necessary for us to retain. Your data is stored according to the following retention schedule: 

  1. **Retention schedule**
    1. **After 5 years of inactivity, candidates' personal data will be anonymised.** Activity of a candidate includes: logging-in into the CharityJob website, creating a job alert on CharityJob, opening an email, contacting us online, applying for a job online on CharityJob. 
    2. **After 30 years of inactivity, recruiters' data will be deleted.** Activity of a recruiter includes: logging-in into the CharityJob website, opening an email, contacting us online, downloading the CharityJob rate-card, posting a job on CharityJob. 
  2. **Retention cessation.** If you request to delete your data, then the data will stop being retained and deleted or anonymised immediately. 

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to CharityJob; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

Though CharityJob is based within the United Kingdom and is subject to GDPR, there are instances where we may send information outside of the UK, EU or EEA, due to the nature of CharityJob (a job board) and the technologies required (transmission of data via Internet), your data may be transferred to a destination outside the EEA. 

In such scenario, we ensure that we transfer the minimum amount of data necessary enter legal contracts to with these third parties to ensure your data is treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the European levels of data protection. 

**You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes.** We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by not checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d2bbbcb4bd92b1bab3a0bba6abb8bdb0fcb1bdfca7b9). 

**You have the right to withdraw your consent to the processing of your personal data by submitting a written request to that effect to[ [email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#31585f575e71525950435845485b5e531f525e1f445a).**

Furthermore, if you believe any of the personal data we hold about you is inaccurate, please tell us so we can correct it as necessary. 

**You always have the right to request for the deletion of your data.** We have a formal process which we will follow if you decide you would no longer like us to retain our data. We will follow our usual customer service response and be in touch to confirm we have received the request in less than four business hours (Monday to Friday from 9am to 5:30pm). Once the request has been received, it will take 7 business days for it to be completed. Please e-mail [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#046d6a626b44676c65766d707d6e6b662a676b2a716f) if you would like to request deletion of your data. 

**If you are unhappy with the way your personal data has been processed by us, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner's Office through their site[www.ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/).**

The CharityJob website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites. 

This Privacy Policy gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You can email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) Any access request will be subject to a fee of 10 pounds to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you. 

Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy. 

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#0f666169604f6c676e7d667b7665606d216c60217a64).
